

Muhammad Alfienda Rahman

Yogyakarta, Indonesia Mobile: (+62) 82225931369

Email: <u>alfinmuhamad0224@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/alfin0224/

Profile

Passionate about building beautiful and modern websites to fulfill needs and solve problems in a business process. A forward-thinking and curiosity-driven web developer who offers more than 4 years experience in web development by writing clean, efficient, reusable, and reliable code for various business processes such as Pertamina RU IV Cilacap, Halfway house for Children with Cancer and Blood Disorders, various provincial government systems, and Sefeo English.

Work Experience

Fullstack Developer (Remote)

02/2023 - 05/2023

Sefeo English

I help developed web applications that are used as advertising media, manage membership data and program data for learning activities in the sefeo english community, as a Fullstack Developer using React, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, NodeJs Express, and MySql Database. Main Achievement: Developed Responsive web frontend code, backend code and Mysql Database.

Web Developer (Remote)

DPMK Provinsi Papua Barat

09/2022-12/2022

West Papua province village-owned business entity registration system

This application is used as a medium for registering the legality of village-owned enterprises within the province of West Papua, as a Fullstack Developer using HTML5 / CSS, Bootstrap4, JQuery, PHP CI, and phpmyadmin.

Key Achievements: Developed Responsive web frontend code, PHP Backend code, and SQL Database.

07/2022-09/2022

SNIPER (Program and Activity Planning Information System) DPMK in West Papua Province

This application is used to input program planning data and activities in each DPMK field which will be submitted to the SIPD application (regional development information system), as a Fullstack Developer using HTML5 / CSS, Bootstrap4, JQuery, PHP CI, and phpmyadmin.

Key Achievements: Developed Responsive web frontend code, PHP Backend code, and SQL Database.

03/2022-06/2022

Digital Office at DPMK Office of West Papua Province

This application is used as a medium for processing and archiving incoming letters, outgoing letters, and other important files within the DPMK's internal scope, As a Fullstack Developer using HTML5 / CSS, Bootstrap4, JQuery, PHP CI, and phpmyadmin.

Key Achievements: Developed Responsive web frontend code, PHP Backend code, and SQL Database.

01/2022-04/2022

SIKAMPUNG (Village Information System) DPMK Office of West Papua Province

Sikampung is an web system used for data collection and data processing of 1.15 million residents of West Papua province which will later be integrated with the dukcapil population system. As a Front End and Database engineer using HTML5 / CSS, Bootstrap4, JQuery, PHP Laravel, and phpmyadmin.

Key Achievements: Developed Responsive web frontend code and SQL Database.

Web Developer

DISKOMINFOPERSTATIK PROVINSI PAPUA BARAT

07/2020 - 12/2021

I worked on quite a number of projects for various West Papua Provincial Government agencies. Every project, I am entrusted with the responsibility as a frontend developer, backend developer, and database engineer. Also due to the limited number of team members, meanwhile there were various projects that needed to be completed which made me hold more than one position at a time in every web development project.

Key Achievements:

- Developed Responsive Web Frontend Code, and SQL Database of the West Papua Province SIKM (Entry Permit System).
- Developed Responsive Web Frontend Code, PHP Backend Code, and SQL Database
 PPID (Information and Documentation Management Officer)
 DISKOMINFOPERSTATIK West Papua Province.
- Developed PHP Backend Code, and SQL Database of the West Papua Province SITANDA (Letter and Archive Management Application).
- Developed Responsive Web Frontend Code, and SQL Database of Sectoral Data System BAPPEDA West Papua Province.
- Developed Fullstack Responsive Web OPD of the West Papua Province Governance.

06/2019 - 06/2020

I was responsible for developed and customized frontend code and SQL database in the development and maintenance of regional planning and budgeting web system or commonly

called *E-PLANNING*, *E-BUDGETING*, and *E-MUSRENBANG* that suit the business process needs of the West Papua provincial government. This application uses the PHP programming language and the database uses postgreesql.

Key Achievements:

Develop regional planning, musrenbang and budgeting web system in accordance with national laws and provincial regional regulations to assist transparency and security in regional budgeting for the province of West Papua.

The accompanying team from BAPPEDA, provincial DPRD and BPKAD made the regional development budgeting a success. Develop and Maintain low crash application.

Education

Bachelor of Informatics

08/2014 - 01/2019

Universitas Islam Indonesia, Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Excel in Software Development Module (Object-Oriented Programming, Software Engineering, and Web Engineering), graduate with honor (cum laude). Final GPA: 3.61/4.00

Research Experience

Halfway House Management System for Children with Cancer and Blood Disorders 09/2018 – 12/2018

Bachelor Thesis

Created an application that handles registration issues, data collection on room availability, patient medical record data collection, and other internal data collection for child cancer patient shelters which is a non-profit social activity. The result of this study is a web-based management system for pediatric patients with cancer and blood disorders.

Realtime Network Monitoring System for All Areas of PT. PERTAMINA (Persero) RU IV CILACAP 01/2018 – 03/2018

Internship

Create an application that handles network monitoring issues throughout the Pertamina RU IV Cilacap area. The results of this study are a web-based network monitoring system for the entire area of PT Pertamina Pertamina Persero RU IV Cilacap.

Organization Experience

Laboratory Public Relation Coordinator

08/2017 - 01/2018

Informatics Laboratory of Universitas Islam Indonesia

Manage through the informatics lab media with other assistants (4 people) in providing information announcements related to practicum for 1 semester. Compile information whenever there is information that must be announced for one semester. Coordinate with department staff and lecturers to ensure that information related to the announced practicum can be conveyed properly.

Laboratory Assistant

08/2016 - 01/2018

Informatics Laboratory of Universitas Islam Indonesia

Responsible for handling the activities of approximately 250 lab participants in several practicum classes (Database Engineering, Object-Oriented Programming, Web Engineering). Collaborated with lecturers, and graded the students' practicum evaluations.

Publications

Halfway House Management System for Children with Cancer and Blood Disorders

R. Kurniawan and M. A. Rahman, "Halfway House Management System for Children with Cancer and Blood Disorders", 2019, Universitas Islam Indonesia.

Realtime Network Monitoring System for All Areas of PT. PERTAMINA (Persero) RU IV CILACAP 05/2018

F. Rahma and M. A. Rahman, "Realtime Network Monitoring System for All Areas of PT. PERTAMINA (Persero) RU IV CILACAP", 2018, Universitas Islam Indonesia

Web Application Module

08/2017

Informatics Laboratory Member 2016-2017 Universitas Islam Indonesia, 2017.

Object-Oriented Programming Module

02/2017

Informatics Laboratory Member 2016-2017 Universitas Islam Indonesia, 2017.

Database Module 08/2016

Informatics Laboratory Member 2015-2016 Universitas Islam Indonesia, 2016.

Professional/Technical Skills

Hard Skills: HTML5 / CSS, Tailwind CSS, React, Vue.js, Material UI, Bootstrap4, NodeJS Express, REST API, JSON, MySQL Database, PostgreeSql, MongoDB, Git,

Javascript, Jquery, PHP, CodeIgniter, Laravel, SDLC, UI/UX, Microservices,

Monolith, AWS, OOP, VS Code.

Soft Skills: Problem Solving, Analytical Thinking, Creative Thinking, Time Management,

Leadership, Teamwork.

Languages

Indonesia : Native proficiency

English : Intermediate